gradleaders.com 2019-03-20

# Privacy Policy | GradLeaders

## Privacy Policy

GradLeaders.com and CSOResearch.com (the "Websites") are operated by GradLeaders, LLC and GradLeaders, Inc., (collectively "GradLeaders") located at 5980 Wilcox Place, Dublin, Ohio, 43016 USA.  GradLeaders takes the private nature your personal information very seriously. This privacy policy describes how we collect, use and disclose the personal information of visitors and uses of the Websites.  This privacy policy applies only to information collected by GradLeaders through the Websites.  Please read this notice very carefully.

BY USING THE WEBSITES, YOU EXPRESSLY CONSENT TO THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY.

### The Information We Collect

The Websites are only for users over 13 years of age and GradLeaders does not knowingly collect the personal information of any person under 13 years of age.

When you visit the Websites, the Websites will collect personal information about you to give you the best user experience possible. During the registration process you will be asked to input personal information to create an account such as name, email address, city, state and zip code and may be asked additional profile questions regarding your use of the Websites.

If you make a purchase on the Websites, we collect credit card information to complete the purchase. We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) which encrypts or codes all the credit card information we collect and transmit to protect against unauthorized access to your credit card information. GradLeaders collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of your interaction with the Websites.

When you visit the Websites, the Websites may collect anonymous, aggregated data regarding your activities. This anonymous, aggregated data cannot be linked or otherwise used to identify you. GradLeaders’ purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how visitors use the Websites. We may share aggregated information that includes non-identifying information with third parties for industry analysis and demographic profiling. Users of the Websites shall not be entitled to any compensation stemming from the use of such aggregated or non-identifying information. In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using to access the Websites, including the type of device, the operating system, device settings, device identifiers and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. To learn more about the information your device makes available to us, please review the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider.

We do not collect personal information automatically, but we may tie this information to personal information about you that we collect from other sources or you provide to us.

_Resume and Career Profile_

You may also choose to upload additional information, such as your resume and career profile, to improve your experience and use of the Websites.  When you upload your résumé it will integrated into GradLeaders' School Résumé Database that is available for purchase by other users of the Websites.  Information you submit to the Websites and make public via any public posting or application process, may also be available to other Users or those using the Websites and may be available to third party search engines. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information to the extent that you upload any applications. We are not responsible for any Personal Information you chose to disclose on the Websites.  Each User with access to your information will be permitted to use the information in the same manner as if you submitted the information directly to that User.  GradLeaders makes no endorsement or representations and is not responsible regarding the information privacy practices of any User. Any information you choose to make publically available may reveal, or allow others to identify, your nationality, ethnic origin, gender, age, and other aspects of your life. Publicly posting any information on the Websites is entirely voluntary on your part.  You may choose not to allow any of your information to be accessible or transferred to third parties, however, this choice may limit your access to the full use of the Services.

_For School and Employer Users_

By accessing and using the Websites you explicitly agree to use any candidate data you view on or through the Websites (“Candidate Data”) only to the extent reasonably necessary to consider a candidate for the applicable position or other authorized purpose.  You agree to use, disclose, protect and destroy Candidate Data in accordance with this policy.  Specifically, you agree not to disclose Candidate Data to any third party except as otherwise provided in this policy.  You agree to provide candidates the option to update, correct and delete Candidate Data upon a candidate’s request.  You agree to securely destroy Candidate Data once it is no longer necessary to consider a candidate for a position.  You agree to provide reasonable security to protect Candidate Data from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.  Please be aware that your failure to abide by the terms of this policy may result in legal liabilities and obligations _.  _

### Use of Cookies and Web Beacons

As you use the Services, certain information may also be collected passively, including your Internet protocol (IP) address and the browser that you use to visit the Site. GradLeaders may also store a small text file called a "Cookie" on your computer to store your login information (if any) and your personal preferences for the Websites.  GradLeaders may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them). While you will still be able to use the Websites if you disable Cookies in your browser, certain parts of the Websites may not function as effectively. After you register and enable Cookies, we may associate this information with personal information that we have collected from you.

Pages of our Website may contain small electronic files known as web beacons (also referred to as clear gifs, pixel tags, and single-pixel gifs) that permit the Company, for example, to count users who have visited those pages and for other related website statistics (for example, recording the popularity of certain website content and verifying system and server integrity).

Use and Disclosure of your Personal Information

GradLeaders will use the personal information you submit to us to provide you full access and functionality of the Websites.  Accordingly, personal information may be used for the following purposes: (i) to provide and improve our services, features and content; (ii) to administer your  use of our services and accounts; (iii) to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Websites; (iv) to better understand your needs and interests; (v) to fulfill requests you may make; (vi) to personalize your experience; (vii) to provide you with announcements, notifications related to your use of the Websites and other communications such as electronic newsletters, promotional e-mails or similar messaging; (viii) to provide service announcements; (ix) to protect against users seeking to hack into the Websites; and (x) to assess the level of general interest in the Websites and specific information included in the Websites.

Personal information is accessible only by those employees and consultants who have a reasonable need to access such information in order for us to fulfill contractual, legal and professional obligations. All of our employees and consultants have entered into strict confidentiality agreements, and/or have been subjected to thorough criminal background checks requiring that they maintain the confidentiality of personal information.

Except as provided elsewhere in this policy GradLeaders will not disclose your personal information to third parties outside of GradLeaders and its service providers, affiliates, vendors and business partners unless GradLeaders has the good faith belief that disclosure is reasonably necessary to:

  * cooperate with law enforcement authorities or comply with legal process served on GradLeaders or the Websites including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements;
  * protect the property and rights of GradLeaders, its affiliates or a third party;
  * protect the safety of the public or any person;
  * prevent or stop any activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical, inappropriate or legally actionable;
  * complete, as permitted by law, a business sale, asset transfer, merger, acquisition or reorganization; or
  * fix or debug problems with the Websites servers, software or service.

During the normal course of doing business, we may share your information only among those business units, our affiliates and unaffiliated third parties that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf or to provide Website services, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. If GradLeaders discloses your personal information pursuant to one of the above-mentioned conditions, it will do so only to the extent necessary.

We may also disclose your personally-identifying information if you expressly consent to the disclosure.

In some instances, you may opt out of particular third party disclosures or uses of your data by reaching out to support@gradleaders.com to opt out of employer access to your data.

### Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

  * **Tracking Technologies and Advertising**. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. To learn how you can manage your Flash cookie settings, visit the Flash player settings page on Adobe’s website. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly.
  * **Promotional Offers from the Company**. If you do not wish to have your information used by the Company to promote our own or third parties’ products or services, you can opt-out by emailing marketing@gradleaders.com.  If we have sent you a promotional email, you may send us a return email asking to be omitted from future email distributions. This opt out does not apply to information provided to the Company as a result of a product purchase, warranty registration, product service experience or other transactions.

### How You Can Update, Correct or Delete Your Information

GradLeaders acknowledges the individual’s right to access their personal data for the purpose of updating, editing or deleting it. You can access the information that we collect online and maintain through normal updating methods. To update, correct or delete this information, you can contact our Privacy Officer Darrell Dewese via email (ddewese@gradleaders.com) or via telephone (614.791.9438). We reserve the right to take appropriate steps to authenticate an applicant’s identity, to charge an adequate fee before providing access and to deny requests, except as required by the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework.

Your account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so may result in your not being able to access or receive certain services.

### Destruction of Your Personal Data

GradLeaders will store your personal information only so long as necessary to fulfill the purpose for its collection. Once the storage of your personal information is no longer necessary, GradLeaders will securely destroy your data to protect it from unauthorized use or disclosure.

Security of your Personal Information

GradLeaders is committed to protecting your personal information. We regularly test our facilities and use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure.

### Third Party Practices

The Websites may contain links to other web sites that are not owned or controlled by GradLeaders. The provision of such links is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such web sites or location or its contents. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other web sites.

GradLeaders may be potentially liable for the onward transfer of personal data to third parties. GradLeaders will not transfer any personal information to a third-party without first ensuring that the third-party adheres to the Privacy Shield principles. GradLeaders does not transfer personal information to unrelated third parties, unless lawfully directed by a client, or in certain limited or exceptional circumstances in accordance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework.

In the event that GradLeaders is requested to transfer personal data to an unrelated third party, GradLeaders will ensure that such party enters into a written agreement with the third party requiring them to provide protections consistent with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework. 

Personal information is accessible only by those employees and consultants who have a reasonable need to access such information in order for us to fulfill contractual, legal and professional obligations. All of our employees and consultants have entered into strict confidentiality agreements, and/or have been subjected to thorough criminal background checks requiring that they maintain the confidentiality of personal information.

### **Annual Assessment**

GradLeaders assures compliance with this EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Policy and the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework by utilizing the self-assessment approach as specified by the US Department of Commerce. The assessment is conducted on an annual basis to ensure that all of GradLeader’s relevant privacy practices are being followed in conformance with this EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Policy and the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework. Any employee that GradLeaders determines is in violation of these policies will be subject to discipline, up to and including termination of employment and/or criminal prosecution.

### **Applicability**

GradLeaders is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

### Privacy Policy Changes

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy from time to time without notice. When material updates are made, the date of the last revision will be reflected at the end of the page. This page may be bookmarked to facilitate periodic review of this Privacy Policy and to note recent updates.  Please review this privacy policy each time you visit the Websites so that you will be apprised of any changes.  Your continued use of the Websites subsequent to any posted changes to this Policy means you accept those changes.  We will provide notice to you if these changes are material and, where required by applicable law, we will obtain your consent.  Neither this Privacy Policy nor updates to it will affect or modify any contracts we have with our clients.

### Data Transfers

For users outside the United States, please note that any personally-identifiable information you enter into the Websites will be transferred out of your country and into the United States. You consent to such transfer through your use of the Websites. You also warrant that you have the right to transfer such information outside your country and into the United States.

### Your California Privacy Rights

A business subject to California Civil Code section 1798.83 is required to disclose to its California customers, upon request, the identity of any third parties to whom the business has disclosed personal information within the previous calendar year, along with the type of personal information disclosed, for the third parties' direct marketing purposes.

If you are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please send an email to [support@gradleaders.com](mailto:support@gradleaders.com).

### Contact Us

You have the right to access your information to verify its accuracy.  To access your information, ask questions about our privacy practices, or issue a complaint, contact our Privacy Officer Darrell Dewese at:

GradLeaders, LLC  
5980 Wilcox Place,  
Dublin, Ohio, 43016 USA.  
(614) 791-9000   
Email Address: ddewese@gradleaders.com
